<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://coldam.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coldam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-22T10:37:11-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://coldam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cory Gassner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gassner.cory@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TEDxKC 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://coldam.github.io/blog/2013/08/22/tedxkc-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-22T09:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://coldam.github.io/blog/2013/08/22/tedxkc-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple nights ago I attended <a href="http://www.tedxkc.org/">TEDxKC 2013</a> at the Kauffman Center for the Performing Arts.  This was the first one with my girlfriend; she seemed to enjoy it.</p>

<iframe src="http://new.livestream.com/accounts/50006/events/2310121/videos/27836342/player?autoPlay=false&height=360&mute=false&width=640" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>


<p>(Starts at 16:02)</p>

<p>There were some inspiring presenters.  <a href="http://philinthecircle.com/">Phil Hansen</a> was one of those that stood out to me.  He is an artist who used just used dots to make his artwork.  In college, he developed a bad case of arthritis.  His dots were looking more like slashes.
The harder he held his pen the worse his hands became till he couldn&rsquo;t even draw a straight line.  He embraced this constraint and has made several awesome pieces of artwork using constraints as the basis.
Anne Mahlum&rsquo;s story was also touching.  She founded <a href="http://www.backonmyfeet.org/">Back On My Feet</a>, an organization that gets homeless people involved in a running group to help them get control of their lives again.
<a href="http://psych.ku.edu/people/faculty/ilardi_stephen.shtml">Steve Ilardi</a> is a neuroscientist who talked about all the benefits of exercise and sun on our brain.  Also how those things, and every experience, helps mold our brain and can fight mental illnesses such as anxiety and stress.
Jared Ficklin&rsquo;s gondola rides as a means of public transportation was something I had not thought of before.  Wayne White was pretty funny and has lived an interesting life as an artist, art director, illustrator, and puppeteer.  But what really blew my mind was a singer named
<a href="http://www.petermulvey.com/">Peter Mulvey</a>.  He recited a letter he&rsquo;d written to a baby niece of his about a conversation he had with an astrophysicist.  He asked the question &ldquo;Are we all alone out here in this vast universe?&rdquo; and the response took me aback.
The response the astrophysicist gave went something like this.  Consider the entire universe the size of a beach ball.  We are a tiny point on that beach ball.  But mankind&rsquo;s shelf life isn&rsquo;t very long compared to eternity.  We are only a pinprick on one side of the beachball.
There are bound to be other pinpricks by intelligent life throughout time, but the chances of two pinpricks near each other and at the same time is very small.  So, for the most part, yes, we are probably alone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TEDxKC]]></title>
    <link href="http://coldam.github.io/blog/2013/08/20/tedxkc/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-20T12:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://coldam.github.io/blog/2013/08/20/tedxkc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I am attending my second TEDx event in Kansas City.  Last time I went, in 2012, I was introduced to the TED remix.</p>

<h3>It&#8217;s Time for TED </h3>


<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://coldam.github.io//www.youtube.com/embed/vDHET3aCI2U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I was also introduced to the lovely Amber Rubarth (<a href="http://www.amberrubarth.com">http://www.amberrubarth.com</a>) and a host of other excellent presenters.</p>

<p>The most memorable of the talks was about the possibility of using our eye as our login information.</p>

<h3>Extreme Identity: Jeff Carter at TEDxKC</h3>


<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://coldam.github.io//www.youtube.com/embed/Vs8EpSd9ZOg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
